I think we all can agree that cardio is
a crucial aspect of fitness and rowing
machines like the HydroWave are a great
alternative to your standard treadmill
or exercise bike since not only are they
going to improve your cardio they're
also going to tone your muscles at the
exact same time this rower offers
automatic adjustments to the magnetic
resistance features a 16 inch
touchscreen monitor and it can be stored
vertically to make the most of your
available space I've been using the wave
a whole lot lately and I hope you all
are ready because we got a lot to talk
about today so let's go ahead and get
after it
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I've got the hydro wave rower now
if you don't know how this whole process
works in this video today I'm going to
tell you everything you need to know
about this piece of equipment from the
price and the features some of my pros
and cons and of course who should or
maybe should not buy one of these now
pump the brakes real quick before I get
going with all that I have no choice I
gotta let you know we've reviewed a ton
of rowers on barbin.com and you know
what we did we went ahead and made a
best list so if you want to check that
out all you got to do is search barbin
best rowing machines and you can find
out for yourself which ones that we like
the best
okay so let's talk about some of my
favorite things about the wave and I
think first and foremost we've got to
talk about the magnetic resistance so
this actually has auto adjust technology
and so just to explain what that means
really quick the more leg drive you
create while you're rowing you're gonna
have more resistance you know with that
drag during your workouts and vice versa
so the less leg drive you have the
easier it's going to be hopefully that
makes sense for you guys it has a
relatively small footprint and plus you
can always purchase that vertical Wall
anchor and store it vertically to make
the most of your available space the 16
inch touchscreen monitor is what's going
to gain you access to all those Hydro
classes with your membership of course
and in addition to those rowing classes
there's also strength training yoga and
pilates you know right there at your
fingertips which is just really cool the
seat is relatively comfortable compared
to you know other rowers that are on the
market this is also a relatively quiet
machine overall I mean honestly you know
aside from the music and the trainers
that played during those classes the
seat might make more noise than the
actual resistance does
[Music]
all right so let's talk about a few
potential cons and we got to talk about
the money first since this is you know a
luxury rower you're gonna be paying a
luxury price tag which is about nineteen
hundred dollars I'm going to expand on
all this in a minute but that's a pretty
good chunk of change well I ultimately
think it's you know worthy of that price
tag it just might not be in everybody's
wheelhouse also in addition to that
you're gonna have to pay 44 a month at
least for your monthly membership you
know two hydro and there's not any
programmed workouts on this console
right here which might be a bit of a
bummer for some people as well there's
not a fan built in anywhere right here
and that's not the most common thing in
the world when it comes to rowing
machines but that still would be you
know a nice little perk I guess you
could say because if you don't already
know
growing workouts are going to make you
sweat and then lastly you know the
handle here it's it's not horrible by
any means necessary whatsoever but it
can be a little bit slippery at times so
I think just overall if it had a little
bit more of a you know grippier texture
I think that would be a massive benefit
for pretty much everybody involved
[Music]
foreign
so as promised let's talk about some
money now and before I start doing that
I gotta remind you guys you know
products like this the prices are
absolutely subject to change so what's
that saying you know yesterday's price
is not today's price so that's
definitely the case right here so right
now as I'm making this video the base
price of the HydroWave is right around
nineteen hundred dollars but final price
tag you're gonna pay is going to be
determined by a few different factors so
let's talk about that first all right so
we gotta talk about the yearly
membership plan so let's say you want to
go with the one-year plan you're gonna
be paying about 2 400 bucks a two-year
plan we'll see this raise up to around
29.50 or so in the three year plan
that's going to run you around 3 500
bucks and while you can always go and
purchase a one-year membership plan from
that accessories tab on the hydro
website this is actually the only time
you're going to be able to purchase a
multi-year plan so definitely keep that
in mind you know yes gonna cost you more
money up front but in the long run it's
actually going to save you a little bit
of money now let's say you want your
rotor to be a different color than the
stock Black Op option that we have here
well it's going to run you around 300
bucks that vertical Wall anchor I
mentioned earlier it's about 200 the two
year extended warranty plan is roughly
150 and that three-year plan is about
two hundred dollars now there's also
some accessories you can add if you want
there's a machine mat for about 90 bucks
they have their own headphones as well
for about 120 dollars so you know a few
different options there you can always
add on to now if you're absolutely sold
on the wave you just simply you know
can't stomach the fact it's you know
spending a few thousand dollars right up
front Hydro is going to allow you to
finance this purchase through clono so
definitely check out those options as
well
foreign
so let's shift gears here and talk a
little bit about the hydro membership so
once again the only opportunity you have
to purchase one of those multi-year
membership plans is when you're going to
purchase your hydro now if you want to
go for that monthly membership it's
going to cost you about 44 bucks a month
or you know once again you can always go
and add that one year membership plan
you know at any time on its own that's
going to run you around 530 dollars now
I gotta be honest you know this is
pretty pricey compared to a lot of other
membership plans out there but I mean
odds are you're gonna have you know more
available classes at your disposal you
know right here at your fingertips then
you'll really know what to do with and
these aren't just limited to rowing you
know once again you'll have access to
strength training yoga Pilates classes
and there's even circuits that you know
incorporate rowing and strength training
at the same time so every single one of
these classes you know they're led by a
trainer they're going to consist of you
know an intro to the class a little bit
of a warm-up the actual workout I think
you'll kind of cool off too so that's
really nice as well Hydro also has their
own companion app that you can download
to your phone and all of your workout
history stats everything it's going to
sync to that app and that's really
helpful you know for obvious reasons
you're able to keep track of your
progress over time you know which is
really cool plus it also syncs through
Apple Health which you know just that's
just useful as well now as you're going
to you know look for classes and this is
actually the same case with the monitor
right here you can filter all the
workouts based off trainer duration you
know workout style there's a lot of
different options right there for you to
choose from which I just found to be
extremely helpful
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features of the hydro
wave let's talk about this rail first it
is in fact made of stainless steel which
is really nice but the rest of the
framework here is in fact made of a
thermoplastic polymer now it might be a
little bit of a red flag for some people
right off the bat but I'll be honest you
know
I don't see any issues with it you know
seems pretty durable and I don't think
you'll have any problems just so long as
you know you're not Reckless with it so
from the top of the monitor to the floor
is 43 inches it's right around 80 inches
long and about 19 inches wide or so so
you know that compact design is going to
be really nice for people you know who
are tight on Space plus remember you can
store it vertically if you do in fact go
after that wall mount the wave only
weighs about 100 pounds maybe 102 pounds
so it's going to be pretty easy for you
to move it around your personal space
especially since you know you do have a
set of wheels right here at the front
now there is not a designated handle but
you can always just grab right here on
the back of the rail and that's you know
gonna take care of that for you now
despite it being lightweight it has a
375 pound weight capacity which is
actually you know pretty impressive now
let's talk about the handle for a second
it's okay it's not it's not bad it has a
little bit of a rubbery texture I guess
but for the most part it feels pretty
plasticky and you know that could you
know limit your grip at certain times
and that's something you definitely
don't really want now the pedals are
nice they're oversized there's also
seven different adjustment points you
can you know accommodate for your feet
plus they allow for ankle flexion while
you're working out and that's obviously
you know a really nice thing let's talk
about the seat I personally enjoy it
it's pretty foamy you know it's pretty
comfortable to sit on and I think we all
can get behind that right there now
remember you do have automatic
adjustments to the magnetic resistance
on the wave right here now these levels
once again are 50 to 300 but that
default setting of 104 is really just
the most natural I don't think you're
gonna have to do you know any
adjustments unless you just really want
to and automatic adjustments are all
done by the amount of leg drive you
provide while you're working out so
that's really nice you know if you're
really pushing off your feet you're
gonna feel that drag you know be more
difficult and it's gonna be harder to
pull that bar to your chest while you're
working out Bluetooth capabilities make
it possible for you to pair your
favorite earbuds or a heart rate monitor
you know that way you can always track
your heart rate variability which is a
really nice training tool the 16 inch
touchscreen monitor is really easy for
you to navigate and the two speakers
right here they're going to provide some
pretty solid sound as you're working out
another really cool thing here is the
music there's a lot of you know fresh
and oldies throwback there's a lot of
really cool music on here that are just
gonna you know help you you know push
through those tough workouts
[Music]
all right
all right guys so I just want to show
y'all up close you know the full fine
details of this rower once again this is
a stainless steel rail right here so
that's really nice but you know the
framework starting here for the rest of
it it's a thermoplastic polymer I don't
think you're gonna have any issues with
it it's actually pretty nice you know
that sounds pretty pretty pretty durable
to me you know and that's going to lead
to it you know only weighing 100 pounds
but it's also pretty strong once again
that 375 pound weight capacity that's
really nice so move a little bit further
down here and let's talk about the seat
for a second I really like it as you can
see you know that does have a little bit
of give a little bit of cushion and it's
pretty comfortable to sit on honestly
this is the loudest part other than the
speaker so as you can hear
foreign
that's really going to be most of what
you're hearing as you're working out so
that's honestly pretty nice now I also
really like these foot pedals they're
oversized as you can see right here
there's seven different adjustment
points for you to use and it's really
simple to do you can just pop that out
push this up or you know pull it down
and just like that you know a matter of
seconds you're good to go and either a
little bit of ankle flexion is provided
right here during your workouts and
that's obviously a really nice touch now
your magnetic resistance is in fact you
know right here in this drum it's really
nice you can't see it or anything like
that
this handle you know I think some work
could be done overall it's really not
bad maybe I'm being dramatic about it
but you know my grip sometimes isn't the
best you know you start working up a
sweat like really really hardcore with
these rowers so that could be you know a
little bit of an improvement and then
you know you do have a strap right here
that connects the handle you know to the
resistance right here so that's just
going to add to that overall you know
reduced noise level I guess you could
say now let's take a second and talk
about this monitor right here because
this is really the star of the show all
right so I just want to showcase you
know how you operate this touchscreen
monitor and just show you all the
features it has honestly really cool so
as soon as you hop on you know actually
here I'll we'll backtrack a little bit
so whenever you you know turn it on Hop
everything on you'll have the option you
know select your profile you can have
four profiles total which is really nice
so we're gonna click on mine take a
second for it to loads honestly it's
pretty quick interface now it's going to
pop up you know recommended for you and
there's multiple options right here for
you to choose from and they're all it
showcases you know how many minutes each
one is so that's really nice so as you
scroll down it's gonna find a workout
live circuit Drive sweat breathe
Strength yoga Pilates like I said
earlier there's a lot right here to do
so programs right here you know learn to
row Fitness Builder and I think it's
cool how there's you know it's it
categorizes I guess you could say it's
three intro workouts you know nine
workouts beginner you know take a trip
six destinations I like that a lot and
it'll even show you you know the new
like upcoming live workouts that will be
going on and once again it sticks with
the duration of it and everything so
that's nice featured is down here you
know all the different athletes that are
on here listed right here that's really
nice popular workouts and there's even
you know a getting started tab so that
way you know how to properly row and
everything like that so if you go to
library you know at the top right here
I mean all all the classes are right
here and you can categorize by athlete
duration type style location music
there's 4 500 workouts available if you
can knock that Knock Out All 4 500 of
these you know give me a call because
that's really impressive there's a lot
going on here it's a progress tab you
got your profile tab right here you know
name height weight all that stuff help
FAQs Hydro 101 go to your settings here
this is where you know you'll set up
your Wi-Fi your heart rate monitor
Bluetooth audio
factory reset there's a lot going on
right here guys I mean it's almost
overwhelming at times so we're gonna go
right here we're just gonna pop into
this 15 minute number three find your
Rhythm Road click on it and look you got
a little bit of a description right here
it'll tell you whether or not you have
your Bluetooth devices connected you can
edit your sound and your drag settings
right here and this is what I was
talking about so that 104 resistance
that you know that's the default setting
I really like it you know it really
provides that natural feeling of being
on an open body of water but if you want
bring it down to 50 or you know if
you're a daredevil you're gonna bring it
all the way up to 300 so we're gonna you
know we're just gonna stick with that
104 so I can get it to land perfect for
me right there turn your captions you
know all that good stuff right here
we're just going to click row
matter of seconds got all your stuff
pulled up right here you got your split
time you know your 500 meter average
total meters calories beats per minute
you know time remaining this is right
now you know referring to that you know
intro the warm-up setting and then it'll
also you know kind of pin you head to
head against you know other Hydro
members and you know you that way you
know if you're like if you're somebody
like me and you like competition you can
always go head to head against other
people all right y'all so since I just
showed you you know how to operate the
touchscreen monitor I'm going to talk
about the app for a second just kind of
you know how it correlates and you know
how it works so beginning of the month I
haven't been able to get in a bunch of
workouts here in just a couple of days
so that's why you're only seeing a
little bit here but anyways so once you
get on the app you know everything's
going to be categorized you have live
schedule right here on the top you know
strength and movement if you click on it
you know it's going to show you all the
strength and movement so you got 20
minute Pilates five minute course during
10 minute morning Mobility bunch of you
know good stuff right here yoga and
awareness circuit Drive sweat I mean
there's same thing as the monitor
whole lot going on right here all right
so there's a feed you can follow members
and kind of see what's going on across
the hydro Community which is cool you do
have your activity tab right here you
know once again you got your profile
followers following like I said I've
only done a couple workouts past two
days don't come at me right now if you
go to more there's just a few different
options right here Hydro 101 and stuff
like that so it's really nice just to
show you I'm just gonna you know pop on
this 20 minute Adventure one it still
shows you a description and you know it
categorizes the music by Rock and you
can invite people to it click row right
here and one quick thing I forgot let's
go to the filters tab
you know same as the the monitor you
know athlete duration type workout style
location I mean there's so many
locations it's kind of overwhelming
honestly and then music as well so
honestly you know the fact that both of
these sync up and they're relatively
similar the same it's a really nice
touch
foreign
the hydro wave rower well honestly y'all
it's one of my personal favorite rowers
on the market auto adjust technology is
just super unique it's a really nice
touch in my opinion since it you know
directly you know correlates to your
overall efforts which is you know a
really nice thing also you know if you
really want your workout equipment to be
tech savvy I think you're gonna
obviously love the auto adjust
technology but also this 16 inch
touchscreen monitor you know it's loaded
with all those available workout classes
super easy to navigate I think you're
gonna like that and then lastly you know
it's pretty Compact and it can you know
be mounted vertically be stored
vertically and it's really going to
allow you to make the most of your
available space so if you are tight on
space this is probably one of your Best
Bets okay so what about the people who
might want to you know not purchase the
hydro wave rower well let's talk about
money you know yes this is one of my
favorite rowers on the market but that
definitely comes with a price tag and
boy does it have one this is an
expensive piece of equipment so if you
are in a tight budget I mean might be
better off you know going after a more
basic rower and this next Point kind of
piggybacks off that again you know in
addition to that expensive price tag
you're gonna have to pay for a monthly
membership just to gain access to the
available classes and you know really
get your money's worth out of this
product and you know there's once again
not any programmed workouts on this
console aside from you know your
standard super basic just manual workout
mode so if you're somebody who doesn't
want to pay a monthly membership and you
know you just want a rower you can hop
on have a few programs follow like heart
rate and stuff like that probably going
to be better off looking for a different
option
[Music]
that's all I got for y'all today on the
hydro wave rower I think this is a super
solid product for a few specific reasons
so once again it is pretty Compact and
it can be stored vertically to really
allow you to make the most of your
available space you know in your home
gym that magnetic resistance is also
virtually silent when you're working out
so it's not like you're going to drive
you know your roommates your family
members you know whatever something like
you're going to drive anybody crazy just
remember you know this is a pretty
expensive product and you do have to pay
for a membership fee just to you know
really get the full experience thanks
for hanging out with me all I hope this
video was extremely helpful and that I
was able to break down everything you
need to know about this rower right here
as always keep your eyes peeled for my
next video but for now why don't you
head over to barbin.com because we have
a full written article just waiting for
you to read all you got to do is search
bar Bend HydroWave rower review it's
going to pull right up for you and you
can go over everything that we talked
about here today I'll catch on next time